You can think of DISTINCT this way,
يمكنكم التفكير في DISTINCT بهذه الطريقة،
if you want to group by some columns but you don't
إذا كنتم تريدون التجميع حسب بعض الأعمدة لكنكم
necessarily want to include any aggregations,
لا تريدون بالضرورة تضمين أي تجميعات،
you can use DISTINCT instead.
يمكنكم استخدام DISTINCT بدلًا من ذلك.
As an example, let's revisit the count of events by
على سبيل المثال، لنعِد النظر في عدد الأحداث حسب
channel by account we looked at in the GROUP BY segment.
القناة بواسطة الحساب الذي ألقينا نظرة عليها في مقطع التجميع حسب.
Notice the row count, 1509.
لاحظوا عدد الصفوف، 1509.
If we get rid of the events column,
إذا تخلصنا من عمود الأحداث،
you can see that the resulting query returns basically the same
يمكنكم معرفة أن الاستعلام الناتج يقوم في الأصل بإرجاع النتائج
results with the same row count.
نفسها مع عدد الصفوف نفسه.
And if we run that query again with DISTINCT,
وإذا أجرينا استعلامًا مجددًا باستخدام DISTINCT،
you can see that the results are the same.
يمكنكم معرفة أن النتائج هي نفسها.
Of course, they don't include the COUNT
بالطبع، إنها لا تتضمن عدد
anymore because we've removed it from our select statement.
بعد الآن لأننا أزلناه من عبارة select.
Since it's no longer in our select statement,
نظرًا لأنه لن يكون موجودًا في عبارة select لدينا بعد الآن،
and since we're no longer doing an aggregation,
ونظرًا لأننا لن نقوم بالتجميع بعد الآن،
we don't need the GROUP LIKE clause either.
فإننا لسنا بحاجة أيضًا إلى عبارة GROUP BY.